yeah yep good morning it's professor
Johanna Sophia of Johanna's raw foods
and your health recovery coach yours yes
yours everybody who's watching your
health recovery coach if you need to
recover from anything so yeah I was just
reading postings on vegans United and
boy I was taken aback the aggressive
argumentations and fights that are going
on the natural healing persons very few
by the way against although know the
doctor knows best persons in the vegan
society so I said to myself yeah I mean
how not far have we come here I'm trying
to tell you you can heal yourself well
yeah I've done it thousands of people
have done it the science supports it but
yeah many need to be believers of that
which is upstair ii my hair beds are so
therefore today is about sleep another
piece of science that's part of the
equation actually another piece of just
nature that's part of the equation look
open your eyes
everything in the world on planet earth
revives while resting revives while
changing even plants changing the
inhaling versus exhaling and you know
even the oceans and flow and tide and go
back and you know there's a breathing
thing going on and the same is true for
the human body it needs to be active
and then it needs to rest and rejuvenate
itself and if we don't have that rest
it cannot rejuvenate itself properly
even if we're like me super healthy
super raw living foods blah blah blah
you know we still need that rest because
yes we can't be up 24/7 for a long
period of time we can do it for a few
nights but we cannot do it for longer
periods of time lest we shorten our life
expectancy considerably or we then need
a recuperation time from such excess so
rest means that your biology changes and
our biology actually even changes
scientifically-proven like we need to
prove how we function we can just look
listen and observe and analyze of what's
happening in nature I mean even there's
an annual rhythm even exactly under the
equator where there aren't that many
distinct seasons there is a rhythm for
certain times of the year so everything
in life has this cycle of activity and
recuperation and activity and your
recuperation and I mean I'm so happy we
only need six to eight hours to
recuperate in our sleep you know it's
not half the time which I'm very
grateful for because I just love being
awake and doing things and seeing things
and experiencing life and that may not
be true for some but it is certainly
true for me I need to tie my shoes and I
see that I don't even have a chair up
because we had house meeting last night
and we put a little table here and you
know that's why my chair is not in the
right place but we're going to do that
right now it is
again Fitness over 50 and sleeping is
just as important and for me rhythmical
exercises are just as important when we
walk it's a rhythm when we run it's a
rhythm when we do any kind of physical
work most of the time it's a rhythm so I
don't see the point in I mean I see the
point in meditation of course but for me
my meditation works well when I'm also
running or when I'm also yeah moving
somehow so that's my meditation and
that's nothing to say about sitting
still meditation it's just to me rhythm
works better and love rhythm and even
though I didn't have good rhythm as I
grew up because it wasn't in the
teaching and doing of my parents or of
the school and well in different ways
but not the sort of regular rhythm of
but walking and hiking with my parents
of course did give me that rhythm there
are other exercises that don't work
typically rhythmically like climbing a
tree for example you know you have to
see where you're going next it doesn't
work like dogs
dum-dum-dum you know regularly um but
you know what I mean
so with this said going to get my chair
going to get ready to do our routine and
[Music]
is all right what I forgot to mention
yesterday and yeah yeah I migrated pants
today I might color I really do like
color I have not enjoyed the changing of
colors as much as in this year in a long
time I don't know that their fall colors
aren't excessively beautiful this year
so if you're in the region you know go
out and enjoy or coming up if you're
down in New York City you know coming up
it is absolutely stunning what's going
on in the color scheme of the trees I
think it depends on how the weather
changes if it's too dry things just go
Brown and if it's too wet you know maybe
the save it somewhere in between is the
magical balance for everything
it's really beautifully red and orange
and some green and it's just you know
these maple trees that have all the
colors in one tree from green to yellow
to orange to red I just completely
indulge in that and find that beautiful
alright another thing is just a brief
word on pain you know that I'm
struggling with the right shoulder
because there's some muscle tissue
missing from birth but and sometimes it
shows up even while running and I
noticed there too you know I can talk to
my brain and say you know stop the pain
relax that part flow etc you know
according to dr. Sarno again dr. science
that is not wah-wah you know we can
direct our nerves to relax and let go
because
this pain is caused by cramping up in
within the tissue and in that area
obviously because it wants to fix
something that is not well but we can
let go of that pain and ask the body to
fix it and it's wonderful how that works
every time
so now I again saying you know we want
to strength through this part and not
experience that s pain all right stretch
up and stretch two three four five six
seven eight and one two three four five
six seven sweet and sweet two three four
five six seven
Oh siren is chasing birds window to
window and squirrels yeah engine ease
keep that back straight I mean it won't
be all straight because as we turn real
course pull the shoulder blades to the
side of that doesn't look around and
sweet two three four and five six seven
eight and swing two three four and five
six seven eight
and again three four and six seven eight
[Music]
hey oh I didn't mark that I did my three
miles yesterday of course and two three
four five six seven eight
so my promise that 23 day commitment is
workout plus three miles or on Sundays
for miles so have you decided whether
you're going to commit to a regular
workout your body cannot get strong
unless you have that regularity just
like with sleep we need it to function
on planet earth you know science fiction
you may have stories where people just
take a pill instead of sleep but biology
on planet Earth tell us different eight
more one two three four five six hold it
on eight and bend your knees even more
and just Jen we twist that body and it
doesn't matter if your body is crooked
here we want that twist and relax
all right that's an easy take this class
stuff I don't really need them and
before back back five six
two three four six yes my right show
that you can do straight up and straight
back round the back and one and yes I
know
can you bring it down to me please thank
you
[Music]
let's keep breathing hold your breath
- and strange shoulder blades together
oh you get more water and snaps so I'm
gonna get it snap nicely okay and that
was short but these are going to be
short as long as I have to also do a 3d
three mile runs so maybe we'll do a
little more back in a little while and
kick two three four and five six seven
eight and here's two three four and five
six seven eight point two three four and
five six seven and eight and heels two
three four five six seven stretch up
let's enter one more time and flat
forward chin forward flat back down as
far as you can and then relax and group
those shoulders and then and I have
reconstitute the straightness as you got
oh I need more water now have water you
but no glass oh there's a glass do that
right now so I can feel my yeah three
miles every day I don't think yeah no I
haven't even done that let alone seven
days a week plus workup so here's to
challenging ourselves to the next level
you can do it too
I'm learning to drink 65 I'm learning to
drink huh yeah I used to really just
join his sippy sippy sippy sip but never
like that all the way down don't know
why and when I'm nice and upright it
does go down easier and also the air
comes out easier that you're never
totally swallow so maybe just me but my
to follow air alright I feel it should
be in a very different position so that
I have more sent here to this nobody is
with that this morning what's up guys
live is that better yeah I should be the
other way around
- so huh all right
well do this for a change and cake 2 3 4
5 6 7 8 and heels
2 3 4 5 6 7 8 and toes
2 3 4 5 6 7 8 mu 2 3 4 5 6 7 8 and
stretch up and relax and stretch here I
hit the wall hit the things I guess
that's why I'm the other way around
and both legs together and one two
because you can just stay seated with
your chair for how with your body facing
forward so you can see the screen and
one two three four five six seven switch
up oh my god I can't do much today huh
the effects of the double whammy and I
did sleep it up it's not that I didn't
who know woke up naturally actually ever
wake up naturally after six hours and
then I want to put it in another hour I
have to really sort of relax myself back
into sleep yes I'm ready to go I'm ready
to bounce up to six hours then trysting
all right other type of flakes we can do
this come on and what two three four and
five six a little to the right and a
little to the left
does the cat so you don't fall over it
just means that the sides get worked a
little bit more than they normally do
and I think we're going to do the kicker
but I'm going to go to west side just
because of the familiarity and kick as
long as you can and wildly in your own
rhythm and and distract yourself as much
as you need to by singing talking
tilting and whatever see I can't go as
fast as I normally go the kicker of
course I hustle wearing these heavy
shoes cuz I'm going running oh and
tonight was Frost
for the first time really 29 degrees
come on you know that's it I still
whatever run
Oh
and barely conscious believing my feet
on the floor it is because I'm lazy two
three four five six seven eight if you
wonder what this is because I was
talking so fast belly
crunches barely crunches and what can
you see it up make sure you sitting
towards the edge two three four and five
six seven again and two two three four
and five six seven eight yeah and if you
were
I ate a bunch esterday but I didn't make
what I really wanted to make by
potassium ooh mix I need to do that
today when you push your muscles you
need a lot of potassium and magnesium to
relax those muscles into just growing in
strength and to not freak and go up a
little you know you stretched me too far
and possibly to muscle fever which
creates an acidity in the muscle and
literally inflammatory situation so we
don't want to do that when poor we need
to stuff our faces with potassium
bananas alone don't seem to do it what I
eat is parsnip carrots Illyria which is
celery root very high in potassium beets
and greens you know so all of them will
provide some potassium especially the
root vegetables and
they also calm down the entire body if
it is if it is muscles have challenged
yeah alright both legs together yeah we
haven't done both legs together that's
why what's missing so not ballet
crunches by both legs together two three
four to the right six seven eight and
center
two three four to the left six seven
eight and Center two three four exhale
and what about belly crunch and we're
getting 208 and you can keep your feet
on the floor depending on them where you
are two three four five six seven eight
and one two three six seven eight Wow
and where is everybody
these are have the wrong setting or is
something wrong with my computer I'm on
public I started 27 minutes ago
sure all right where are you guys so
watching this later you will see that
we're relatively short we're just going
to do a short workout I talked a lot
about sleep off sleep and the importance
of looking what is in nature on planet
Earth
and from that to learn as opposed to the
detail where I should really be after we
understand the basics of how nature
works you know looking into cells and
molecules and atoms should be after we
understand the basic basic rhythms of
the functioning and planet Earth for
example that all life rejuvenates itself
until it has lived its arch and then
deteriorate into
becoming earth again two three four
elbow seven five six seven keep your
knees soft and up two three four and
elbows six seven eight one more and up
two three four and elbows six seven
eight
and we're going straight to the diagonal
but I'm straight
yeah shoulder blades up cause in some of
us stick out more than others and up
back back the emphasis is on back here
putting pushing those shoulder blades
together in the back and eight and stay
and bounce two three four and five six
seven eight relax
it's interesting how with running even
though the legs do the legwork our
entire body of course feels the
challenge and becomes and our heart
needs to do all the pumping all right
one more time understand this way again
knees are soft and back two three four
and five six seven now bombs and bounce
two three four five shoulders head down
seven eight bounce two three four five
six I'm starting to sweat and that's
when we end because I can go sweat when
running that's plenty
yeah everybody this has been fitness
over 50 I did not put the title in but I
will and I've been talking about sleep
so if you didn't get the beginning watch
it listen and the importance of sleep
and why as simple as that is and the
argument of science versus nature as if
there would be such an argument you know
science has to be based in nature
especially human and living in life
science and medicine hello this body is
a piece of nature it functions like
nature you know so often these days I'm
saying what happened to logic in this
world but then again yesterday I was
watching a movie about the time between
and well actually the first world war
time between and the second world war
and it's just you know this family saga
and yeah I mean that was worse it
certainly was worse if you lived
anywhere in Europe anyway and the rest
of the world where those two world wars
really wreak havoc and but yeah people's
understanding people it's not
understanding nature and their own
nature and their own feelings it was
just like yeah it's so true because I
grew up right after the Second World War
with my parents and everybody else still
having all those experiences and living
that lack of understanding their own
nature so we're still stuck in that a
little bit unfortunately
love you guys again this has been
fitness over 50 I am your health
recovery coach yes I can teach you how
to heal yourself naturally overcome all
sorts of diseases diabetes heart disease
cancer digestive tract issues and it's
not that I he or my pill heals you it's
you you just need to learn how how guys
love you